<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:posterous="http://posterous.com/help/rss/1.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Mobile Oxford Technology Blog</title>
    <link>http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com</link>
    <description>Most recent posts at Mobile Oxford Technology Blog</description>
    <generator>posterous.com</generator>
    <link type="application/json" href="http://posterous.com/api/sup_update#1391d9376" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="http://api.friendfeed.com/2008/03#sup"/>
    <atom:link href="http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/rss.xml" rel="self"/>
    <atom:link href="http://posterous.superfeedr.com" rel="hub"/>
    <item>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2011 03:31:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <title>Django, i18n and Molly</title>
      <link>http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/django-i18n-and-molly</link>
      <guid>http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/django-i18n-and-molly</guid>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>
	<p>Here in the Mobile Oxford team, we've been working with the team at <a href="http://www.bangor.ac.uk/" target="_blank">Bangor University</a> to help get the <a href="http://mollyproject.org/" target="_blank">Molly Project</a>, the open source project which grew from Mobile Oxford's code base, ready to be translated into multiple languages (in Bangor's case - Welsh!).</p>
<p>As Molly is a Django project, we can use Django's <a href="https://docs.djangoproject.com/en/dev/topics/i18n/" target="_blank">extensive i18n framework</a> to do most of the work for us, however, this does rely on us marking up the text for translation. When it comes to testing i18n, we needed a quick way of generating a test language file for us to drop in to check we've caught all of the strings that need to be translated.</p>
<p>Inspired by <a href="http://blog.isotoma.com/2010/06/generating-sample-unicode-values-for-testing/" target="_blank">Richard Mitchell at Isotoma, who suggested using upside down English to test for Unicode bugs</a>, we decided that testing i18n using upside-down English makes the most sense for us. <a href="https://github.com/mollyproject/mollyproject/blob/b19a2d6efccb041db4bc626b666764672bf50255/scripts/testlanguage.py" target="_blank">And so, I wrote a script which did this</a>. It ignores formatting strings and inside HTML, but everything else gets inverted using the lookup table defined at the top. We used this as we marked up each app in a feedback loop to make sure everything is marked up, and I think we got everything.</p>
<p>Data from external services (e.g., the library) isn't translated, but where our data sources (e.g., the OpenStreetMap planet.osm dumps and the NaPTAN) do contain multi-lingual data, this is now imported into our database and tagged as the correct language, and where the data exists, it means you'll see it in different languages!</p>
<p>However, we did find a few gotchas with Django's i18n. First of all, there's <a href="https://code.djangoproject.com/ticket/7704" target="_blank">a fairly major bug in Django's makemessages function</a>, which means that the output of makemessages for JavaScript is unreliable as to whether or not we caught all the strings. The only real alternative is to generate a .po file by hand, however we cheated by <a href="https://github.com/mollyproject/mollyproject/commit/c9916356601ac273521c2169d979330572c9680f#molly/media/site/js/dummy.js" target="_blank">creating a 'dummy.js' file</a> which manually contains all the JS scripts, to make sure they're found. However, this does mean we have to update this file every time we add a new string, which is a pain.</p>
<p>We've no plans to launch multiple languages on Mobile Oxford at the moment, but this is perhaps something we can look at in the future - translating the site into multiple languages to make it more useful for tourists to the city!</p>
	
</p>

<p><a href="http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/django-i18n-and-molly">Permalink</a> 

	| <a href="http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/django-i18n-and-molly#comment">Leave a comment&nbsp;&nbsp;&raquo;</a>

</p>]]>
      </description>
      <posterous:author>
        <posterous:userImage>http://files.posterous.com/user_profile_pics/845679/25502_597131478794_222301017_5791877_1339792_n.jpg</posterous:userImage>
        <posterous:profileUrl>http://posterous.com/users/YwNtenERVGp</posterous:profileUrl>
        <posterous:firstName>Chris</posterous:firstName>
        <posterous:lastName>Northwood</posterous:lastName>
        <posterous:nickName>cnorthwood</posterous:nickName>
        <posterous:displayName>Chris Northwood</posterous:displayName>
      </posterous:author>
    </item>
    <item>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2011 09:51:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <title>Oxford term dates</title>
      <link>http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/oxford-term-dates</link>
      <guid>http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/oxford-term-dates</guid>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>
	<p>Just a quick update here from the offices of Mobile Oxford - but if you're a member of Oxford University and develop websites in Python, you'll undoubtedly find it more useful from time-to-time to represent dates in Oxford format - Term, Week, Year, as opposed to a typical calendar date. We've had the same issue, and developed some code to handle this for us - providing us Django template tags for direct use inside Mobile Oxford, as well as a more abstract library other code may find useful.</p>
<p>We've put this on <a href="https://github.com/oucs/oxford-term-dates/" target="_blank">Github</a>, as well as on <a href="http://pypi.python.org/pypi/oxford_term_dates/" target="_blank">PyPI</a>, for you to use and enjoy!</p>
	
</p>

<p><a href="http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/oxford-term-dates">Permalink</a> 

	| <a href="http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/oxford-term-dates#comment">Leave a comment&nbsp;&nbsp;&raquo;</a>

</p>]]>
      </description>
      <posterous:author>
        <posterous:userImage>http://files.posterous.com/user_profile_pics/845679/25502_597131478794_222301017_5791877_1339792_n.jpg</posterous:userImage>
        <posterous:profileUrl>http://posterous.com/users/YwNtenERVGp</posterous:profileUrl>
        <posterous:firstName>Chris</posterous:firstName>
        <posterous:lastName>Northwood</posterous:lastName>
        <posterous:nickName>cnorthwood</posterous:nickName>
        <posterous:displayName>Chris Northwood</posterous:displayName>
      </posterous:author>
    </item>
    <item>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 05:53:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <title>Dev8D - Day 2</title>
      <link>http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/dev8d-day-2</link>
      <guid>http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/dev8d-day-2</guid>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>
	<p>Day two and the natives still haven't discovered that I wouldn't know an LDAP server if it fell on me. My cunning ruse to hide behind two 'real' techies and just smile and nod if anyone starts talking C++ to me seems to be working out fine. I'm just camping in the Basecamp room this morning; there were a couple of interesting looking sessions this morning, but I was a wee bit late getting here and the session I wanted to go to looked like standing room only. We've now used three different forms of public transport in getting too and from the venue and they've all been pretty crowded and rather slow. The bus was probably the best of them. Mine this morning even had the obligatory business man saying "I'm on the bus!" loudly into his mobile. Tsk, honestly, /civilised/ people now /text/ their partners/colleagues/whatever to tell them which mode of transport they're currently enduring.</p>
<p>Still haven't worked out what the '8D' part of Dev8D stands for. Current thinking is that it's the emoticon for 'whoa cool!' it has been really nice running in to old friends and erstwhile colleagues here, and not just the ones from our own dept who we didn't know were coming. I start to realise that the developer community, particularly within higher education, is more finite than it may first appear; even excluding the smart cookies who took the Sun certification their institutions paid for and went off to industry and dreams of avarice. Money isn't everything you know. It can't buy happiness, and it can't buy the sort of job satisfaction you get when someone first installs your dev system, gets it up and running, and claps their hands with glee as they dive in to start realising some of the ideas they had, but lacked the tools to realise. And there's a LOT of that going on here this week; I've done it myself several times.</p>
<p>The network connectivity here has been outstanding so far, though it does seem to have hit a bit of a bottleneck at the moment (thank goodness for offline blogging apps). I'm surprised that it has held up as well as it has actually. There are a couple of network options for delegates; eduroam (huzzah!) and the local wireless offering. This is probably more than adequate to cope with most conferences, but we're talking /developer/ conference here, and we tend to be more connected than most folk. If you know that one of the Arduino projects being spoken about is a moisture sensor to allow your houseplants to post to Twitter when they need watering you'll perhaps start to get an idea of the sheer scale of the logistical problems involved. ULU have coped admirably, and the venue seems ideal for this sort of event. Kudos to all those involved in the organisation, infrastucture, and running of this event; in case no one else says it elsewhere, thank you for all your hard work.</p>
<p>Lunch was, again, superb. Yesterday was 'Taste of Asia' and today, it seems, was 'Taste of the UK', now the UK isn't noted for it's culinary excellence, so the chefs had set themselves quite a task if they were going to top yesterday, but all the old school favourites were there; sausage and mash, fish and chip, garlic prawns and salmon (hang on...) followed by apple crumble with cream (no custard??) or fresh fruit salad. It was, without a doubt, easily up to yesterday's very high standard. The quality of the food will be the one thing I take away from this conference, besides, you know, all the techy stuff...</p>
<p>This afternoon I am going to go and hack with the little Arduino open hardware boards. I think the object is to build a controller for an 8x8 LED matrix so that it will display scrolling message a la Time Square. A challenge indeed, but one which I shall rise to, assuming I don't fall into a buttery mash induced stupor in the meantime.</p>
	
</p>

<p><a href="http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/dev8d-day-2">Permalink</a> 

	| <a href="http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/dev8d-day-2#comment">Leave a comment&nbsp;&nbsp;&raquo;</a>

</p>]]>
      </description>
      <posterous:author>
        <posterous:userImage>http://posterous.com/images/profile/missing-user-75.png</posterous:userImage>
        <posterous:profileUrl>http://posterous.com/users/YHzehrCFRq9</posterous:profileUrl>
        <posterous:firstName></posterous:firstName>
        <posterous:lastName></posterous:lastName>
        <posterous:nickName>csteph</posterous:nickName>
        <posterous:displayName>csteph</posterous:displayName>
      </posterous:author>
    </item>
    <item>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2011 08:04:26 -0800</pubDate>
      <title>JISC Developer Days : dev8d</title>
      <link>http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/jisc-developer-days-dev8d</link>
      <guid>http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/jisc-developer-days-dev8d</guid>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>
	<p><div class='p_embed p_image_embed'>
<a href="http://getfile4.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/mobileoxfordtech/gvEnDJFfmhfwuxrxspmBflupJudeIwipbkfulgrloudzIoIzjBwgnkrcIvio/p70.jpg.scaled1000.jpg"><img alt="P70" height="595" src="http://getfile4.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/mobileoxfordtech/gvEnDJFfmhfwuxrxspmBflupJudeIwipbkfulgrloudzIoIzjBwgnkrcIvio/p70.jpg.scaled595.jpg" width="595" /></a>
<a href="http://getfile3.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/mobileoxfordtech/dCcgdlEHvqpaHugsCawachgfghxCwarkJDmGwvuErHzrtIeFGkpCIsEvaylJ/p72.jpg.scaled1000.jpg"><img alt="P72" height="451" src="http://getfile3.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/mobileoxfordtech/dCcgdlEHvqpaHugsCawachgfghxCwarkJDmGwvuErHzrtIeFGkpCIsEvaylJ/p72.jpg.scaled595.jpg" width="595" /></a>
<a href="http://getfile9.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/mobileoxfordtech/atxryDccieGFvooHqylayilxAHccmbcElpkhtyEJDthxxcbqqHDebeExzzos/p74.jpg.scaled1000.jpg"><img alt="P74" height="963" src="http://getfile4.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/mobileoxfordtech/atxryDccieGFvooHqylayilxAHccmbcElpkhtyEJDthxxcbqqHDebeExzzos/p74.jpg.scaled595.jpg" width="595" /></a>
<div class='p_see_full_gallery'><a href="http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/jisc-developer-days-dev8d">See the full gallery on Posterous</a></div>
</div>
</p>dev8d came along before I was quite ready for it. I'd glanced quickly at the program, but only noticed a bunch of unfamiliar acronyms. I had a nagging feeling that I was going to be a very non-technical fish in the geekiest pond in town. In the car on the way down, however, I started to actually read the program and began to realise that behind the acronyms there were actually some really interesting projects.  <p>We arrived on Tuesday evening and, by the end of the car journey, I had marked far more sessions than I was going to be able to attend. An embarrassment of techie riches, including things which promised to take me way back to a mis-spent youth of hardware hackery; brought bang up to date and involving RFID and open hardware amongst other things. I had to juggle things a bit so that I would be able to help out with our project workshops (which is, after all, why we were here), but otherwise I'd lined up a pretty interesting program for myself.</p><p>After a reasonably comfortable night at the Wembley Plaza (which is every bit as nice a place as it sounds), we caught a very crowded tube into town and were soon at the venue. My expectations began to mellow when I spotted the huge platters of Danish pastries and giant urns of coffee in the basecamp room. These people obviously knew their audience! The basecamp hall has plenty of seating, plenty of power strips, eduroam wireless network (eduroam is so satisfyingly painless to use across the country that seeing it on the list of available networks is as comfortable and reassuring as meeting an old friend). After getting connected, firing off some first impression tweets (under the @mollyproject account) and uploading a few pics to my Dev8D set on Flickr, the day kicked off with some quick introductory talks which were pitched at a nice informal level. It seems that this was going to be the prevailing ethos of the event; come and go from sessions as you please, pick up in the middle, leave if you're bored, la de dah, do as thou wilt shall be the whole of the conference program.</p><p>So, after the pastries and coffee came Arduino; a nice, simple, open, cheap, and well supported little microprocessor board which you can use to make, well, whatever you like really. I worked through the examples (somewhat disappointed that there was no soldering involved - I really like the smell of solder flux...) and picked up enough of the control code to feel confident with it, and even had enough time in the session to play around with some examples of our own (including a rudimentary theremin). My brain was already working ahead and sourcing the hardware so that I could carry this on at home after the conference. I love it when you come out of a session buzzing with creative possibilities.</p><p>Unbelievable, but that was the morning gone already and now lunch, a really spectacularly good lunch, was now being served downstairs. The clink of cutlery punctuated the steady flow of conversation. It seems that a lot of people had been similarly inspired by their morning sessions.</p><p>After lunch I attended a short series of lightening talks, which included some stuff about OAI-PMH; the protocol that refuses to die, which gave me flash-backs to my first stumbling forays into XML After the talks came our first workshop session and I'm here now writing this entry while I should probably be paying attention. I hope nobody asks me anything more complicated than "which way to the coffee?"</p>
	
</p>

<p><a href="http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/jisc-developer-days-dev8d">Permalink</a> 

	| <a href="http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/jisc-developer-days-dev8d#comment">Leave a comment&nbsp;&nbsp;&raquo;</a>

</p>]]>
      </description>
      <posterous:author>
        <posterous:userImage>http://posterous.com/images/profile/missing-user-75.png</posterous:userImage>
        <posterous:profileUrl>http://posterous.com/users/YHzehrCFRq9</posterous:profileUrl>
        <posterous:firstName></posterous:firstName>
        <posterous:lastName></posterous:lastName>
        <posterous:nickName>csteph</posterous:nickName>
        <posterous:displayName>csteph</posterous:displayName>
      </posterous:author>
      <media:content type="image/jpeg" height="2162" width="1336" url="http://getfile7.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/mobileoxfordtech/atxryDccieGFvooHqylayilxAHccmbcElpkhtyEJDthxxcbqqHDebeExzzos/p74.jpg">
        <media:thumbnail height="809" width="500" url="http://getfile1.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/mobileoxfordtech/atxryDccieGFvooHqylayilxAHccmbcElpkhtyEJDthxxcbqqHDebeExzzos/p74.jpg.scaled500.jpg"/>
      </media:content>
      <media:content type="image/jpeg" height="1468" width="1936" url="http://getfile0.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/mobileoxfordtech/dCcgdlEHvqpaHugsCawachgfghxCwarkJDmGwvuErHzrtIeFGkpCIsEvaylJ/p72.jpg">
        <media:thumbnail height="379" width="500" url="http://getfile9.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/mobileoxfordtech/dCcgdlEHvqpaHugsCawachgfghxCwarkJDmGwvuErHzrtIeFGkpCIsEvaylJ/p72.jpg.scaled500.jpg"/>
      </media:content>
      <media:content type="image/jpeg" height="1506" width="1506" url="http://getfile2.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/mobileoxfordtech/gvEnDJFfmhfwuxrxspmBflupJudeIwipbkfulgrloudzIoIzjBwgnkrcIvio/p70.jpg">
        <media:thumbnail height="500" width="500" url="http://getfile0.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/mobileoxfordtech/gvEnDJFfmhfwuxrxspmBflupJudeIwipbkfulgrloudzIoIzjBwgnkrcIvio/p70.jpg.scaled500.jpg"/>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2011 03:43:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <title>Lightning talk on Mobile Oxford at Oxford Geek Night #19 (video)</title>
      <link>http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/lightning-talk-on-mobile-oxford-at-oxford-gee</link>
      <guid>http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/lightning-talk-on-mobile-oxford-at-oxford-gee</guid>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>
	<p>
<p>Just a quick post to stick up this video that was taken of me doing a lightning talk at Oxford Geek Nights explaining what Mobile Oxford does and how people can get involved.</p>
<p><iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/17556309?portrait=0" frameborder="0" height="336" width="595"></iframe></p>
</p>
	
</p>

<p><a href="http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/lightning-talk-on-mobile-oxford-at-oxford-gee">Permalink</a> 

	| <a href="http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/lightning-talk-on-mobile-oxford-at-oxford-gee#comment">Leave a comment&nbsp;&nbsp;&raquo;</a>

</p>]]>
      </description>
      <posterous:author>
        <posterous:userImage>http://files.posterous.com/user_profile_pics/1174082/168936_705580740312_193100659_42240462_4476034_n.jpg</posterous:userImage>
        <posterous:profileUrl>http://posterous.com/users/4aLwT1dLPcD7</posterous:profileUrl>
        <posterous:firstName>Tim</posterous:firstName>
        <posterous:lastName>Fernando</posterous:lastName>
        <posterous:nickName>Tim</posterous:nickName>
        <posterous:displayName>Tim Fernando</posterous:displayName>
      </posterous:author>
    </item>
    <item>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2010 08:31:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <title>ESXi on a GSA (or, installing ESXi from USB key)</title>
      <link>http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/esxi-on-a-gsa-or-installing-esxi-from-usb-key</link>
      <guid>http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/esxi-on-a-gsa-or-installing-esxi-from-usb-key</guid>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>
	<p>Not really a Mobile Oxford or Molly post this time - but all good services need servers to run off, and Mobile Oxford is no different. We've recently freed up a server (a former Google Search Appliance, which is a rebadged Dell PowerEdge 2950), however installing VMWare ESXi server onto it wasn't so straight forward. First off, a GSA doesn't have an optical media drive, and our initial attempts to install it off a USB drive were for naught, mainly because we prepared the USB drive wrong.</p>
<p>So, these were the steps that worked for us:</p>
<ul>
<li>Install Unetbootin (but not a recent version of it, something from the 3.x series will do)</li>
<li>If you're on Linux, make sure you have a 3.x version of SYSLINUX (4.x doesn't work)</li>
<li>Use Unetbootin to install the ESXi ISO onto your USB key</li>
<li>Go into your key, and <a href="http://benincosa.org/blog/?p=171" target="_blank">alter the syslinux.cfg file and add a ks.cfg as detailed in this blog post</a></li>
<li>You can also get an error relating to sectors, <a href="http://www.ivobeerens.nl/?p=699" target="_blank">this blog post describes how to solve it</a>.</li>
<li>Check that virtualisation is all turned on in the BIOS, and it's set to boot from your USB key</li>
</ul>
<p>And it's as simple as that!</p>
	
</p>

<p><a href="http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/esxi-on-a-gsa-or-installing-esxi-from-usb-key">Permalink</a> 

	| <a href="http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/esxi-on-a-gsa-or-installing-esxi-from-usb-key#comment">Leave a comment&nbsp;&nbsp;&raquo;</a>

</p>]]>
      </description>
      <posterous:author>
        <posterous:userImage>http://files.posterous.com/user_profile_pics/845679/25502_597131478794_222301017_5791877_1339792_n.jpg</posterous:userImage>
        <posterous:profileUrl>http://posterous.com/users/YwNtenERVGp</posterous:profileUrl>
        <posterous:firstName>Chris</posterous:firstName>
        <posterous:lastName>Northwood</posterous:lastName>
        <posterous:nickName>cnorthwood</posterous:nickName>
        <posterous:displayName>Chris Northwood</posterous:displayName>
      </posterous:author>
    </item>
    <item>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2010 03:39:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <title>Mobile Oxford version 0.4 coming in the next week!  </title>
      <link>http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/mobile-oxford-version-04-coming-in-the-next-w</link>
      <guid>http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/mobile-oxford-version-04-coming-in-the-next-w</guid>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>
	<p>We'll soon be releasing a new major release of Mobile Oxford, this will bring in many new features, bug fixes and changes in code structure to improve quality and sustainability of the Molly Project.</p>
<p>Quick list of improvements:</p>
<h2>Changes to Mobile Oxford in version 0.4</h2>
<h3>Weblearn</h3>
<h4>Polls</h4>
<ul>
<li> Public Polls now votable without authentication </li>
<li> Polls which allow multiple responses will now work </li>
<li> Polls which you are not allowed to see the results of will now work </li>
</ul>
<h4>Authentication</h4>
<ul>
<li> Fixed a bug where oAuth authentication occasionally looped around from external service (weblearn) a random number of times </li>
<li> Better handling of Weblearn errors and privileges </li>
</ul>
<h3>New Transport Page</h3>
<ul>
<li> We're launching a new transport page which will aggregate a bunch of useful travel information including Oxford live rail departures, the number of free spaces in each of the five Park and Rides, real time bus info from the five nearest bus stops (or your favourite bus stops) and BBC Road Travel Alerts. </li>
</ul>
<h3>Podcasts</h3>
<ul>
<li> ePubs are now detected and downloadable </li>
</ul>
<h3>Favourites Feature</h3>
<ul>
<li> You can now add favourite places which are displayed on the front page and if bus stops will be displayed on the transport page </li>
</ul>
<h3>Search</h3>
<ul>
<li> Fixed a silent bug which missed a couple of search results </li>
<li> Search now allows use of Unicode (which used to cause a 500 error) </li>
<li> Library search now accepts Unicode characters </li>
</ul>
<h3>Places</h3>
<ul>
<li> Minor restyling to match Podcasts </li>
<li> Park and Ride spaces now shown on Park and Ride POI page </li>
<li> Railway Stations for the whole country are now visible and their real time departure boards </li>
<li> You can now click on a train service and see where it stops in text and on a map </li>
<li> You can now choose favourite places which show up on the front page </li>
<li> Points of interest can have 'associated' entries, e.g. a Park and Ride will have associated bus stops </li>
<li> Oxontime bus stop numbers are now displayed bus stop pages </li>
</ul>
<h3>Front Page</h3>
<ul>
<li> Favourite places now displayed on front page </li>
<li> River status no longer displays misleading 'Correct as of X min ago' </li>
</ul>
<h3>Backend Improvements</h3>
<ul>
<li> Caching header improvements should improve responsiveness of site </li>
<li> Opera Mini users get a warning not to use 'Mobile' view as it is the spawn of the devil (makes silly assumptions about HTML) </li>
<li> Feature phones now get slimmed down HTML again </li>
<li> More robust handling of certain race conditions </li>
<li> Various improvements to adhere to HTML standards </li>
</ul>
<p>Check out a full list of improvements on the Mollyproject wiki at: <a href="https://github.com/mollyproject/mollyproject/wiki/Changelog-0.4" title="Mollyproject 0.4 changelog">https://github.com/mollyproject/mollyproject/wiki/Changelog-0.4</a></p>
	
</p>

<p><a href="http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/mobile-oxford-version-04-coming-in-the-next-w">Permalink</a> 

	| <a href="http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/mobile-oxford-version-04-coming-in-the-next-w#comment">Leave a comment&nbsp;&nbsp;&raquo;</a>

</p>]]>
      </description>
      <posterous:author>
        <posterous:userImage>http://files.posterous.com/user_profile_pics/1174082/168936_705580740312_193100659_42240462_4476034_n.jpg</posterous:userImage>
        <posterous:profileUrl>http://posterous.com/users/4aLwT1dLPcD7</posterous:profileUrl>
        <posterous:firstName>Tim</posterous:firstName>
        <posterous:lastName>Fernando</posterous:lastName>
        <posterous:nickName>Tim</posterous:nickName>
        <posterous:displayName>Tim Fernando</posterous:displayName>
      </posterous:author>
    </item>
    <item>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2010 06:48:43 -0800</pubDate>
      <title>News Section Re-skin</title>
      <link>http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/34937801</link>
      <guid>http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/34937801</guid>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>
	<div style="color: #000000; font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 13px; background-color: #ffffff; margin: 8px;">
<p style="color: #000000; font-size: 13px; font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif;">The initial problem was that the news section design didn't sit well with other sections like Podcasts. The layout of elements and the use of colour was not felt to be making the best use of the possibilities and I began to look at how the design could be made more unified and consistant and at what quick wins could be implemented to give the design a bit more visual impact.</p>
<p style="color: #000000; font-size: 13px; font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif;">The First, and relatively trivial task was to amend the page templates involved in the news section so that they used the same CSS for section title and article text as the equivalent elements in the Podcast section. I did this and pushed the changes to git as part of the Bigcleanup branch. These changes have already been merged to the live site and the section now at least looks more like it belongs with the others.</p>
<p style="color: #000000; font-size: 13px; font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif;"><div class='p_embed p_image_embed'>
<img alt="Img_2043" height="338" src="http://getfile1.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/FGllxztdCFxsBpHfHJAcnwBfcyvqBdrdeHlfCkffEplavyojlFhgGbmJdkuE/IMG_2043.PNG.scaled595.png" width="300" />
<img alt="Img_2045" height="335" src="http://getfile2.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/cxooaHpzvEaEeuwrtkytikbHhEHEnitgpvbFgIEmdFAmDhinAEzIHEkzGffx/IMG_2045.PNG.scaled595.png" width="300" />
<div class='p_see_full_gallery'><a href="http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/34937801">See the full gallery on Posterous</a></div>
</div>
</p>
<p style="color: #000000; font-size: 13px; font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif;">Surveying other news and news-like sites though suggests that we may be missing a trick or two. Some example of mobile news sites are the BBC News native iPhone app, The mobile version of iPlayer. Google Reader's mobile version, and IMDB.</p>
<p style="color: #000000; font-size: 13px; font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif;"><div class='p_embed p_image_embed'>
<a href="http://getfile5.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/BCrszwkcHDoItyGaBgHEoaqehilflmteFBlqDxwgFnzgwcBvIeGFoJqBmqsm/IMG_2047.PNG.scaled1000.png"><img alt="Img_2047" height="770" src="http://getfile5.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/BCrszwkcHDoItyGaBgHEoaqehilflmteFBlqDxwgFnzgwcBvIeGFoJqBmqsm/IMG_2047.PNG.scaled595.png" width="595" /></a>
<img alt="Img_2048" height="391" src="http://getfile4.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/bEJCgtptvxrEclAgxqqhImBAmGGdjxoJlgwvsCqbwvrvIlvdcHfaukHlGbxd/IMG_2048.PNG.scaled595.png" width="300" />
<img alt="Img_2049" height="432" src="http://getfile5.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/IgsqIsojhvrDBiHkvmmfgEvDzsIkqxCGjzxDjaqfwqBbrDiluHolHoJjfzlI/IMG_2049.PNG.scaled595.png" width="300" />
<img alt="Img_2050" height="418" src="http://getfile3.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/upaebeBwysaDisBguxfncCrkEuAnpqIaCsrkDsnFkwnbnwuhGxulzscjxsCu/IMG_2050.PNG.scaled595.png" width="300" />
<div class='p_see_full_gallery'><a href="http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/34937801">See the full gallery on Posterous</a></div>
</div>
</p>
<p style="color: #000000; font-size: 13px; font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif;">These sites all give a positive and usable mobile experience and have some common features which we could learn from. With the exception of the Google Reader site they all reserve a small amount of space at the top of the page to display the title and nothing else (the BBC News site does also use this space to display a couple of controls, but, as a native app rather than a mobile site it is able to do this more easily). They all make use of colour to a greater or lesser extent, to highlight important navigational or functional aspects of the current page (see particularly the iPlayer's somewhat eye-popping pink and how well that highlights important info against the dark/black background). The all make full use of the screen real estate, particularly the page width, to display content.</p>
<p style="color: #000000; font-size: 13px; font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif;">I think we could quite easily add a little more colour to the site - judicious, but subtle accent colours - to not only make the design a little more lively, but to draw the eye to important page elements. I think where the current news section design lets itself down somewhat is in not making use of the entire screen width. I can see that the nice, rounded corner boxes have a certain aesthetic appeal, but those few pixels they lose to either side are more valuable perhaps than they would be in an equivalent desktop site. Pushing the width out like this though, would have a knock on effect on the design of the section headers which would lose their rounded corners and drop shadows. I would propose either switching the section title with the subsequent links to give a dark blue title with white/pale grey links beneath or (or possibly and) a subtle gradienton the section title to bring it forward a bit.</p>
<p style="color: #000000; font-size: 13px; font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif;">On the subject of colour, I have a couple of examples of its effective use from non-news mobile sites.</p>
<p style="color: #000000; font-size: 13px;"><div class='p_embed p_image_embed'>
<img alt="Britekite2" height="357" src="http://getfile4.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/EFCCfyerkqtlEobJAprbCnJtbxxldwIsFtsnEdGazherhhHjIfjoBdqvspqz/britekite2.jpg.scaled595.jpg" width="320" />
<img alt="Mailchimp" height="416" src="http://getfile2.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/fnvlzqBauHlpnxzwjqAubjuaGxzBmExnkuttzBbslsJizCAnnvCDAFDHsaEi/mailchimp.jpg.scaled595.jpg" width="320" />
<a href="http://getfile4.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/nDJvdEHnIAwyawGldzgwFqlDtxJFBynAumswGauoCBjmAADwsiBjhtyoooqF/meebo3.jpg.scaled1000.jpg"><img alt="Meebo3" height="387" src="http://getfile1.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/nDJvdEHnIAwyawGldzgwFqlDtxJFBynAumswGauoCBjmAADwsiBjhtyoooqF/meebo3.jpg.scaled595.jpg" width="595" /></a>
<img alt="Britekite" height="416" src="http://getfile5.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/mkebEjzvGziCfwpmADDzxdBsGHznDdaCvHaegcujgeDcxFyGxuDxicsAvavh/britekite.jpg.scaled595.jpg" width="320" />
<img alt="Viget-labs" height="416" src="http://getfile8.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/nHbfcmykxmHCCoudDimeifdBxbcFereEvoexepsDGinxChxCyiqatAbyopns/viget-labs.jpg.scaled595.jpg" width="320" />
<div class='p_see_full_gallery'><a href="http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/34937801">See the full gallery on Posterous</a></div>
</div>
</p>
<p style="color: #000000; font-size: 13px;">The basic scheme &nbsp;of the Mobile Oxford site is a rather monochromatic blue and grey-blue and the brown accent colour (which is actually slightly off in terms of where the natural compliment to the main blue would fall on a colour wheel) is used in a way which dissipates it's impact as an accent, and it becomes a seemingly rather odd choice of alternate background colour. While I appreciate that monochrome colour schemes translate better to a range of devices and degrade more gracefully to greyscale, I think that we can learn from how others have used colour in the same context.</p>
<p style="color: #000000; font-size: 13px;">The BrightKite, Meebo, Mailchimp and Viget sites all use a similar palette to ours. Meebo and Viget have the overall blue being highlighted by a lively orange. At the sub-page level they drop back, wisely I feel, to a plain white background. The orange used by Meebo and Viget is the bog standard complimentary colour to the dominant blue. BrightKite have gone a slightly different route and used one of the accent colours from an analogic triad - in this case a rather lurid (in isolation) green. The Mailchimp site uses a similar palette, but reverses main and highlight colours.</p>
<p style="color: #000000; font-size: 13px;"><span style="font-size: 12px; color: #424037; line-height: 21px;">Thoughts?</span></p>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
	
</p>

<p><a href="http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/34937801">Permalink</a> 

	| <a href="http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/34937801#comment">Leave a comment&nbsp;&nbsp;&raquo;</a>

</p>]]>
      </description>
      <posterous:author>
        <posterous:userImage>http://posterous.com/images/profile/missing-user-75.png</posterous:userImage>
        <posterous:profileUrl>http://posterous.com/users/YHzehrCFRq9</posterous:profileUrl>
        <posterous:firstName></posterous:firstName>
        <posterous:lastName></posterous:lastName>
        <posterous:nickName>csteph</posterous:nickName>
        <posterous:displayName>csteph</posterous:displayName>
      </posterous:author>
      <media:content type="image/png" height="338" width="300" url="http://getfile0.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/FGllxztdCFxsBpHfHJAcnwBfcyvqBdrdeHlfCkffEplavyojlFhgGbmJdkuE/IMG_2043.PNG">
        <media:thumbnail height="338" width="300" url="http://getfile0.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/FGllxztdCFxsBpHfHJAcnwBfcyvqBdrdeHlfCkffEplavyojlFhgGbmJdkuE/IMG_2043.PNG.scaled500.png"/>
      </media:content>
      <media:content type="image/png" height="335" width="300" url="http://getfile2.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/cxooaHpzvEaEeuwrtkytikbHhEHEnitgpvbFgIEmdFAmDhinAEzIHEkzGffx/IMG_2045.PNG">
        <media:thumbnail height="335" width="300" url="http://getfile3.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/cxooaHpzvEaEeuwrtkytikbHhEHEnitgpvbFgIEmdFAmDhinAEzIHEkzGffx/IMG_2045.PNG.scaled500.png"/>
      </media:content>
      <media:content type="image/png" height="828" width="640" url="http://getfile1.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/BCrszwkcHDoItyGaBgHEoaqehilflmteFBlqDxwgFnzgwcBvIeGFoJqBmqsm/IMG_2047.PNG">
        <media:thumbnail height="647" width="500" url="http://getfile7.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/BCrszwkcHDoItyGaBgHEoaqehilflmteFBlqDxwgFnzgwcBvIeGFoJqBmqsm/IMG_2047.PNG.scaled500.png"/>
      </media:content>
      <media:content type="image/png" height="391" width="300" url="http://getfile5.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/bEJCgtptvxrEclAgxqqhImBAmGGdjxoJlgwvsCqbwvrvIlvdcHfaukHlGbxd/IMG_2048.PNG">
        <media:thumbnail height="391" width="300" url="http://getfile4.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/bEJCgtptvxrEclAgxqqhImBAmGGdjxoJlgwvsCqbwvrvIlvdcHfaukHlGbxd/IMG_2048.PNG.scaled500.png"/>
      </media:content>
      <media:content type="image/png" height="432" width="300" url="http://getfile8.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/IgsqIsojhvrDBiHkvmmfgEvDzsIkqxCGjzxDjaqfwqBbrDiluHolHoJjfzlI/IMG_2049.PNG">
        <media:thumbnail height="432" width="300" url="http://getfile1.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/IgsqIsojhvrDBiHkvmmfgEvDzsIkqxCGjzxDjaqfwqBbrDiluHolHoJjfzlI/IMG_2049.PNG.scaled500.png"/>
      </media:content>
      <media:content type="image/png" height="418" width="300" url="http://getfile2.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/upaebeBwysaDisBguxfncCrkEuAnpqIaCsrkDsnFkwnbnwuhGxulzscjxsCu/IMG_2050.PNG">
        <media:thumbnail height="418" width="300" url="http://getfile8.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/upaebeBwysaDisBguxfncCrkEuAnpqIaCsrkDsnFkwnbnwuhGxulzscjxsCu/IMG_2050.PNG.scaled500.png"/>
      </media:content>
      <media:content type="image/jpeg" height="357" width="320" url="http://getfile2.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/EFCCfyerkqtlEobJAprbCnJtbxxldwIsFtsnEdGazherhhHjIfjoBdqvspqz/britekite2.jpg">
        <media:thumbnail height="357" width="320" url="http://getfile9.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/EFCCfyerkqtlEobJAprbCnJtbxxldwIsFtsnEdGazherhhHjIfjoBdqvspqz/britekite2.jpg.scaled500.jpg"/>
      </media:content>
      <media:content type="image/jpeg" height="416" width="320" url="http://getfile6.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/fnvlzqBauHlpnxzwjqAubjuaGxzBmExnkuttzBbslsJizCAnnvCDAFDHsaEi/mailchimp.jpg">
        <media:thumbnail height="416" width="320" url="http://getfile4.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/fnvlzqBauHlpnxzwjqAubjuaGxzBmExnkuttzBbslsJizCAnnvCDAFDHsaEi/mailchimp.jpg.scaled500.jpg"/>
      </media:content>
      <media:content type="image/jpeg" height="416" width="640" url="http://getfile7.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/nDJvdEHnIAwyawGldzgwFqlDtxJFBynAumswGauoCBjmAADwsiBjhtyoooqF/meebo3.jpg">
        <media:thumbnail height="325" width="500" url="http://getfile3.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/nDJvdEHnIAwyawGldzgwFqlDtxJFBynAumswGauoCBjmAADwsiBjhtyoooqF/meebo3.jpg.scaled500.jpg"/>
      </media:content>
      <media:content type="image/jpeg" height="416" width="320" url="http://getfile0.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/mkebEjzvGziCfwpmADDzxdBsGHznDdaCvHaegcujgeDcxFyGxuDxicsAvavh/britekite.jpg">
        <media:thumbnail height="416" width="320" url="http://getfile8.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/mkebEjzvGziCfwpmADDzxdBsGHznDdaCvHaegcujgeDcxFyGxuDxicsAvavh/britekite.jpg.scaled500.jpg"/>
      </media:content>
      <media:content type="image/jpeg" height="416" width="320" url="http://getfile7.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/nHbfcmykxmHCCoudDimeifdBxbcFereEvoexepsDGinxChxCyiqatAbyopns/viget-labs.jpg">
        <media:thumbnail height="416" width="320" url="http://getfile1.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/nHbfcmykxmHCCoudDimeifdBxbcFereEvoexepsDGinxChxCyiqatAbyopns/viget-labs.jpg.scaled500.jpg"/>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2010 03:41:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <title>Making the open source Molly Project more 'open'</title>
      <link>http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/making-the-open-source-molly-project-more-ope</link>
      <guid>http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/making-the-open-source-molly-project-more-ope</guid>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>
	<p>Recently we've been thinking hard about how to develop the Molly project into a true community open source project.&nbsp;</p>
<h3>Moving away from SourceForge</h3>
<p>The Molly Project has been hosted on sourceforge.net for a while now. And whilst sourceforge gave us a wide range of tools on paper, the lack of structure, multiple passwords and general mismatch of tools set the bar to contributing rather high. Even we as primary contributors found it hard to use their issue tracker.</p>
<p><div class='p_embed p_image_embed'>
<a href="http://getfile5.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/GigmJAwHulwtmbiCHpwGrHwwaIfHrCwHahoijopDHggoiwcloDsjyBolkhdb/SourceForge.net_Molly_Feature_Settings.png.scaled1000.png"><img alt="Sourceforge" height="455" src="http://getfile7.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/GigmJAwHulwtmbiCHpwGrHwwaIfHrCwHahoijopDHggoiwcloDsjyBolkhdb/SourceForge.net_Molly_Feature_Settings.png.scaled595.png" width="595" /></a>
</div>
</p>
<p>So we set out to look for alternatives and the first that came to mind was Github. After a quick analysis of alternatives we decided to settle down there not least due to its large community of users, enhancing the chances of our code being forked (<a href="http://zef.me/3369/how-git-encourages-open-source-contribution" title="An article titled: How git encourages open source contribution">why forking is a good thing</a>). It also provided team and organisation tools which let us easily set up different types of members in a project and a great lightweight issue tracker and multi-markup wiki.&nbsp;Even simple things like adding READMEs in supported markup languages means that Github will display them inline to the project page.</p>
<p><div class='p_embed p_image_embed'>
<a href="http://getfile9.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/fqbAafEkDJlADnuccbvhlmbzBdhfrvAzvzioqDIgJBCImnsloqGdlquyxIpc/Issues_-_mollyproject_mollyproject_-_GitHub.png.scaled1000.png"><img alt="Issues_-_mollyproject_mollyproject_-_github" height="444" src="http://getfile6.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/fqbAafEkDJlADnuccbvhlmbzBdhfrvAzvzioqDIgJBCImnsloqGdlquyxIpc/Issues_-_mollyproject_mollyproject_-_GitHub.png.scaled595.png" width="595" /></a>
</div>
</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Of course by moving to Github, we would be losing one of the primary reasons for going with sourceforge in the first place - mailing lists. So we kept our three mailing lists on sourceforge but moved everything else over.</p>
<p>But the longer I think about it the less I think mailing lists are entirely necessary. We have three lists, 'users', 'developers' and 'commits'. The users' list has had all of two posts to it, the 'commits' list has had automated commits which can now be subscribed to on github (even in an <a href="https://github.com/mollyproject/mollyproject/commits/master.atom" title="Atom feed of mollyproject commits">Atom feed</a>). This left the developer list, which although has had various ongoing discussions the chatter hasn't been as strong as we would have liked. Of course we'll continue to keep the developer mailing list running for the&nbsp;foreseeable&nbsp;future and it&nbsp;will be interesting to see which means of sharing turns out best.&nbsp;</p>
<h3>Mailing Lists, Forum, a Knowledge Base, E-Mails</h3>
<p>Something that rather surprised us was that some developers seem to be a bit hesitant in using IRC or mailing lists. Perhaps these methods are now too 'old hat'? We would often get direct email queries but very few directed to the mailing lists which were supposed to harness the spirit of open source.</p>
<p>Enter <a href="http://tenderapp" title="Link to Tender App">'Tender'</a> as used by various organisations including Github themselves. We had identified Tender as part of our on going analysis on service management tools for Mobile Oxford. In essence it provides an integrated support system, including email ticketing, FAQs, public discussions (not dissimilar to forums, but with some subtle differences) and even more excitingly, provides free accounts for open source projects.</p>
<p><div class='p_embed p_image_embed'>
<img alt="Save_image" height="249" src="http://getfile5.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/FcijqjDgrhqojDyflIyqBrllwgIcfIduswjcedFiHmxlJEJyjxCbjJEJikxu/save_image.png.scaled595.png" width="400" />
</div>
</p>
<p>In the next few days we will be launching our 'tender' at <a href="http://support.mollyproject.org" title="Molly Project's support site as provided by tenderapp.com"> <a href="http://support.mollyproject.org">http://support.mollyproject.org</a></a> and the aim is the have as much developer (and perhaps management?) discussion as possible out here on the web, where hopefully it's less scary.</p>
<h3>Why not use your host institution's tools?</h3>
<p>We could indeed have used the extensive tools supplied by our own institution, but we felt it important that the Molly Project tried to keep its own identity and reduce the chances of the project being seen as entirely 'owned' by Oxford University. After all, we are trying to create a true open community project.</p>
<h3>Cleaning up code</h3>
<p>Mobile Oxford's initial iterations were not intended for production service and thus the code base has evolved organically. There has been much cruft left over from failed experiments, old systems integration and so on. Earlier this year we set up a project with Oxford Brookes to deploy a version of Molly for them. This proved a little hard at first, but we made significant changes to the structure of the project to improve portability. Now, we're making another bash at it in earnest. &nbsp;</p>
<p>Taking from the excellent lead of a project named <a href="http://mobilewebosp.pbworks.com/" title="Mobile Web OSP based on PHP">Mobile Web OSP</a> (which provides similar functionality to the Molly Project but is written in PHP) we're now working on really 'opening up' the code with the following steps:</p>
<ol>
<li>Remove as much redundant old code (cruft) as possible.</li>
<li>Reduce code dependencies.</li>
<li>Improve install scripts and reduce the entry barrier to use.</li>
</ol>
<p>With a few hours work we managed to remove a fair bit of old and confusing code, a few more hours and we managed to remove five Python dependencies including one that had given several people problems in the past (PyCairo). Whilst we carry on trimming the code, we're also writing install scripts iteratively and will soon be making this part of a continuous integration server.</p>
<p><div class='p_embed p_image_embed'>
<a href="http://getfile2.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/wHEsfJdxchrHgJyJgbFxmbjIsfJuxdCAfyBIeEAeHABtsEtqJHodGihaigkc/The_mollyproject_Network_-_GitHub.png.scaled1000.png"><img alt="The_mollyproject_network_-_github" height="257" src="http://getfile8.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/wHEsfJdxchrHgJyJgbFxmbjIsfJuxdCAfyBIeEAeHABtsEtqJHodGihaigkc/The_mollyproject_Network_-_GitHub.png.scaled595.png" width="595" /></a>
</div>
</p>
<p>We're aiming for two major releases in the next two months, the first being version 0.4 which will bring a new transport application and a number of major tweaks. Next in January 2011, we will launch version 0.9 which is currently being developed as part of the '<a href="https://github.com/mollyproject/mollyproject/tree/thebigcleanup" title="Molly Project - the big cleanup development branch">the big cleanup</a>' branch on github.</p>
	
</p>

<p><a href="http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/making-the-open-source-molly-project-more-ope">Permalink</a> 

	| <a href="http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/making-the-open-source-molly-project-more-ope#comment">Leave a comment&nbsp;&nbsp;&raquo;</a>

</p>]]>
      </description>
      <posterous:author>
        <posterous:userImage>http://files.posterous.com/user_profile_pics/1174082/168936_705580740312_193100659_42240462_4476034_n.jpg</posterous:userImage>
        <posterous:profileUrl>http://posterous.com/users/4aLwT1dLPcD7</posterous:profileUrl>
        <posterous:firstName>Tim</posterous:firstName>
        <posterous:lastName>Fernando</posterous:lastName>
        <posterous:nickName>Tim</posterous:nickName>
        <posterous:displayName>Tim Fernando</posterous:displayName>
      </posterous:author>
      <media:content type="image/png" height="249" width="400" url="http://getfile9.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/FcijqjDgrhqojDyflIyqBrllwgIcfIduswjcedFiHmxlJEJyjxCbjJEJikxu/save_image.png">
        <media:thumbnail height="249" width="400" url="http://getfile5.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/FcijqjDgrhqojDyflIyqBrllwgIcfIduswjcedFiHmxlJEJyjxCbjJEJikxu/save_image.png.scaled500.png"/>
      </media:content>
      <media:content type="image/png" height="584" width="782" url="http://getfile9.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/fqbAafEkDJlADnuccbvhlmbzBdhfrvAzvzioqDIgJBCImnsloqGdlquyxIpc/Issues_-_mollyproject_mollyproject_-_GitHub.png">
        <media:thumbnail height="373" width="500" url="http://getfile3.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/fqbAafEkDJlADnuccbvhlmbzBdhfrvAzvzioqDIgJBCImnsloqGdlquyxIpc/Issues_-_mollyproject_mollyproject_-_GitHub.png.scaled500.png"/>
      </media:content>
      <media:content type="image/png" height="574" width="750" url="http://getfile0.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/GigmJAwHulwtmbiCHpwGrHwwaIfHrCwHahoijopDHggoiwcloDsjyBolkhdb/SourceForge.net_Molly_Feature_Settings.png">
        <media:thumbnail height="383" width="500" url="http://getfile4.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/GigmJAwHulwtmbiCHpwGrHwwaIfHrCwHahoijopDHggoiwcloDsjyBolkhdb/SourceForge.net_Molly_Feature_Settings.png.scaled500.png"/>
      </media:content>
      <media:content type="image/png" height="416" width="963" url="http://getfile8.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/wHEsfJdxchrHgJyJgbFxmbjIsfJuxdCAfyBIeEAeHABtsEtqJHodGihaigkc/The_mollyproject_Network_-_GitHub.png">
        <media:thumbnail height="216" width="500" url="http://getfile0.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2010-11-30/wHEsfJdxchrHgJyJgbFxmbjIsfJuxdCAfyBIeEAeHABtsEtqJHodGihaigkc/The_mollyproject_Network_-_GitHub.png.scaled500.png"/>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2010 03:03:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <title>Secure off-site media with Django-Compress</title>
      <link>http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/33885695</link>
      <guid>http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/33885695</guid>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>
	<div style="color: #000000; font-family: Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 13px; background-color: #ffffff; margin: 8px;">
<p>The next version of Mobile Oxford will coincide with several improvements to our server infrastructure, including off-loading our static content to a second, dedicated, Lighttpd server, however this deployment wasn't just as simple as changing the MEDIA_URL setting in the Django config. Because we use SSL for certain parts of the website, we need to set our media to load from our static server using https, but setting the MEDIA_URL requires the protocol to be specified when using a full URL (previously we just used a relative one, which meant we didn't have an issue).</p>
<p>A&nbsp;<a href="http://djangosnippets.org/snippets/1754/" target="_blank">Django snippet</a>&nbsp;revealed a context processor (which is now&nbsp;<a href="https://github.com/mollyproject/mollyproject/commit/08b0505c71ad028a6d632a71a2c58e641900c109" target="_blank">in molly.utils</a>) to dynamically alter the MEDIA_URL template tag based on whether or not the request is secure, but we use&nbsp;<a href="http://code.google.com/p/django-compress/" target="_blank">django-compress</a>&nbsp;to minify our CSS and JavaScript, which doesn't use the MEDIA_URL template tag to generate it's URLs. Fortunately, we're not the first person to come across this problem, and&nbsp;<a href="https://github.com/mikelim" target="_blank">Michael Lim</a>&nbsp;has&nbsp;<a href="https://github.com/mikelim/django-compress" target="_blank">forked the original django-compress on Github</a>&nbsp;which implements the same logic as the context processor to dynamically alter the URL used for the compress JS and CSS files.</p>
<p>One gotcha however is that this requires the&nbsp;<a href="http://docs.djangoproject.com/en/dev/ref/templates/api/#django-core-context-processors-request" target="_blank">django.core.context_processors.request</a>&nbsp;context processor to be activate, which isn't by default, but<a href="https://github.com/mollyproject/mollyproject/commit/43ee9e1d78ead024e5e9e93e9c6deea1d293e4c6" target="_blank">adding that to the config</a>&nbsp;and we're all set.</p>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
	
</p>

<p><a href="http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/33885695">Permalink</a> 

	| <a href="http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/33885695#comment">Leave a comment&nbsp;&nbsp;&raquo;</a>

</p>]]>
      </description>
      <posterous:author>
        <posterous:userImage>http://files.posterous.com/user_profile_pics/845679/25502_597131478794_222301017_5791877_1339792_n.jpg</posterous:userImage>
        <posterous:profileUrl>http://posterous.com/users/YwNtenERVGp</posterous:profileUrl>
        <posterous:firstName>Chris</posterous:firstName>
        <posterous:lastName>Northwood</posterous:lastName>
        <posterous:nickName>cnorthwood</posterous:nickName>
        <posterous:displayName>Chris Northwood</posterous:displayName>
      </posterous:author>
    </item>
    <item>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2010 09:41:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <title>Exception Tracking and JIRA</title>
      <link>http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/exception-tracking-and-jira</link>
      <guid>http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/exception-tracking-and-jira</guid>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>
	<p>Keeping track of exceptions, especially in a large project like Mobile Oxford, can be at times a challenging task. The solution we currently use is to have an exception generate an e-mail to us, with information about the exception, and the request that caused it. Some clever hashing, combined with a decent e-mail client, allows these e-mails to be threaded, but languishing in our inboxes probably isn't the best way to handle them. Unhandled exceptions are bugs, and should be handled as such within our current bug tracking systems.</p>
<p>One thing we've started doing at Mobile Oxford is looking at the tools we're using, particularly for bug tracking. Previously we used <a href="https://sourceforge.net/projects/mollyproject/" target="_blank">SourceForge</a>, but found its tools to be below the standard we're looking for. We looked at a myriad at other tools - <a href="https://github.com/" target="_blank">Github</a>, <a href="https://launchpad.net/" target="_blank">Launchpad</a>, <a href="http://playnice.ly" target="_blank">Playnice.ly</a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://hoptoadapp.com/">Hoptoad</a> and <a href="https://lighthouseapp.com/">Lighthouse</a>, with mixed reactions. Hoptoad in particular had us interested, especially with the <a href="http://stevelosh.com/projects/django-hoptoad/" target="_blank">django-hoptoad</a>&nbsp;integration, which would make it easy to drop in to the Mobile Oxford deployment, but Lighthouse's issue tracking functionality let it down.</p>
<p>Internally, <a href="http://www.oucs.ox.ac.uk/" target="_blank">OUCS</a> uses <a href="http://www.atlassian.com/software/jira/" target="_blank">JIRA</a> as a tool for bug tracking, which is an insanely powerful tool that does everything we want, and more, so inspired by Hoptoad and the django-hoptoad library, we investigated getting Django reporting exceptions to JIRA, with the same sort of duplication checking, etc - and an afternoon of coding later, we're successful. It's external to the Molly Project, and can be dropped in to any Django project as middleware. There are a few more settings than I'd have liked to see in the finished product, but that just comes down to the massive flexibility of JIRA.</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/cnorthwood/django-jira" target="_blank">The package is hosted on Github</a>, feel free to fork it, and there are some simple instructions in the <a href="https://github.com/cnorthwood/django-jira/blob/master/README" target="_blank">README</a> on how to add it, and the settings that need to be added to your settings.py to get it working - let us know your feedback, if you find it useful, or if you spot any bugs!</p>
	
</p>

<p><a href="http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/exception-tracking-and-jira">Permalink</a> 

	| <a href="http://mobileoxfordtech.posterous.com/exception-tracking-and-jira#comment">Leave a comment&nbsp;&nbsp;&raquo;</a>

</p>]]>
      </description>
      <posterous:author>
        <posterous:userImage>http://files.posterous.com/user_profile_pics/845679/25502_597131478794_222301017_5791877_1339792_n.jpg</posterous:userImage>
        <posterous:profileUrl>http://posterous.com/users/YwNtenERVGp</posterous:profileUrl>
        <posterous:firstName>Chris</posterous:firstName>
        <posterous:lastName>Northwood</posterous:lastName>
        <posterous:nickName>cnorthwood</posterous:nickName>
        <posterous:displayName>Chris Northwood</posterous:displayName>
      </posterous:author>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
